by jerry quinn
jerry quinn is a 2011 inductee born in
county mayo ireland
so was denise dufala by the way one of
my first friends ever here
he led the efforts that led to the
founding of cleveland's irish american
club eastside in 1978
and the male society in 2004. his irish
radio program hasn't been on the air
since 1908.
well good evening everybody
uh what first
congratulate and to say thank you to dan
and debbie hansen
for restoring this event it's been a
great one i've had every one of them and
i just told larry jennifer and i love
meeting all of you every year but
margaret lynch's tenure
as executive director of the irish
american archives society
has been nothing less than spectacular
on the first day she has worked
tirelessly
to promote
and protect our irish heritage
by constantly creating and implementing
new means and methods and focusing not
just on the past but always looking to
the future
the many projects she has overseen such
as
the publishing of the
175-year history of the saint patrick's
day parade
and the history of boxing world champion
johnny kilbane
will be appreciated
by future generations of not only irish
americans but also the citizens of
people
manus
has ensured the importance of irish
america and the history of cleveland
ohio
long
may she continue to do so market
[Applause]
thank you so much jerry one of my
mentors and someone i've admired for so
long and thank you to the hansons and
all of you for this great honor
as far back as i can remember ethnicity
was part of my identity
here's how i grew up
my father's parents were active in the
ancient order of hibernians and their
lady auxiliary
we went to irish picnics at euclid beach
attended dances and fundraisers for
irish missionaries priests at the west
side irish american club
alongside our mother we helped our
grandmother set up aoh card parties and
irish tables at nationality fairs on the
mall downtown
we took irish death dancing lessons from
tessa burke whose father had taught her
and had
we took part in dancing competitions at
the berea fairgrounds and danced at
cultural garden events with judge john b
corgan at the podium
from the sidelines of the saint
patrick's day parade we cheered as my
uncle marched by with the cleveland
police or when my mother was honored as
high burning of the year or my
grandmothers as irish mothers of the
year
as an adult i marched in the parade with
my dad as a guarantor
i brought my own children to dancing
lessons still with tessie burke
and they competed around the world
i helped my mother to set up for laoh st
bridges stay breakfast
then recruited hibernians to help me in
return
and there's a grand
contingent of hibernians here tonight
and i thank them
in 1994 tom campbell a history professor
at cleveland state university known to
many of you
asked me to join the board of a new
group the irish american archives
society
campbell and many others jerry quinn was
one and there's other trustees here
today
built up the resources to hire an
executive director in 2008.
community supporters like the mayo
society then jerry heads
and others have enabled me to fulfill a
calling to tell the story of the irish
in cleveland
perhaps your growing up years were not
so different
we're all here today because we've each
worked to preserve our own heritage
yet we share so much in common
with each other
and with those who are not yet in this
room
those who are still struggling for a
foothold for acceptance
or path to citizenship
that there's room for all of us in the
ethnic tapestry of this city that we all
call home thank you
[Applause]